<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Softwares on TECHELEX Electronics Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.techelex.com/categories/softwares/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Softwares on TECHELEX Electronics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2012-2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 23:46:51 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.techelex.com/categories/softwares/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 3 Software for Design Circuit Layout</title>
      <link>https://blog.techelex.com/software-design-circuit-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 23:46:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.techelex.com/software-design-circuit-layout/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Designing a circuit layout is very important task in electronics engineer life if he/she work in core electronics field. This is a very easy task but if you don’t have a proper instruction or manual then its becomes a very difficult task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a student drawing a circuit layout using hand is always recommended but what if you want to save a space or simply designing your layout using a software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here top 3 software listed which is easiest in terms of functioning and learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning a software for designing a circuit layout is good thing but if you are a beginner or student it’s very difficult to choose a software for your need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In market or web world many software are available for circuit layout designing and here we listed only three software but keep in mind every software is recommended in industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-for-circuit-layout-design:925390c89c5d0bb52029f34de66dba66&#34;&gt;Software for Circuit Layout Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-cadsoft-eagle:925390c89c5d0bb52029f34de66dba66&#34;&gt;1. CadSoft EAGLE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/Cadsoft-Eagle.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cadsoft Eagle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EAGLE provides quality PCB design software with the features that get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For over 20 years, EAGLE has been satisfying design engineers around the world, by offering the same core functionality as expensive commercial software, at the fraction of the cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy to learn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schematic editor, layout editor, library editor modules with identical user interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free service support through dedicated experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compatible with WindowsÂ®, LinuxÂ®, MacÂ®&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/Dtg0Bo&#34; title=&#34;Cadsoft Eagle download&#34;&gt;CadSoft EAGLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is our favorite schematic and layout editor. Its extremely simple and easy to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here a best tutorial for quick start with CadSoft Eagle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/R4DYztYB6d4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-orcad:925390c89c5d0bb52029f34de66dba66&#34;&gt;2. Orcad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/Orcad.png&#34; alt=&#34;Orcad&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OrCAD PCB design solutions provide a complete set of tools to help you achieve the results you need. From the initial schematic to the final artwork, the platform delivers a complete, integrated workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OrCAD tools have a fully open architecture platform. This means you can add unique functionality that is integrated into the program in the form of apps, or you can also build capability and flows yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OrCAD environment offers proven analysis tools for signal integrity, analog and mixed signal, EMI analysis, and much more. All of these tools are seamlessly integrated so there are no translation errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/lgzMaA&#34; title=&#34;OrCAD !6.6 Lite Download&#34;&gt;OrCAD 16.6 Lite Demo Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-express-pcb:925390c89c5d0bb52029f34de66dba66&#34;&gt;3. Express PCB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/expresspcb.png&#34; alt=&#34;Express PCB&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Express PCB software is a snap to learn and use. For the first time, designing circuit boards is simple for the beginner and efficient for the professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It includes ExpressSCH for drawing schematics and ExpressPCB for circuit board layout. The software is easily installed, and a snap to learn and use. Both run with Windows XP through Windows 7.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Software for Design Circuit Diagram</title>
      <link>https://blog.techelex.com/software-design-circuit-diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 22:56:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.techelex.com/software-design-circuit-diagram/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As an electronics engineer designing a circuit diagram is not a big deal. When I was a new student in electronics field teachers teach us to design a circuit diagram using hand, It’s a fun game and i really enjoyed this. But when complexity was increased drawing a circuit diagram using hand is really a bad idea because i want a cleaner tracks and want a better circuit diagram using small piece of PCB (Printed Circuit Board).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that time teachers teach us how to design circuit diagram using software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a time to entered into a software world for designing a circuit diagram it&amp;rsquo;s will amazed you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really amazed like how space saved while designing circuit diagram and simulation of circuit is very interesting. In this post i suggest you a 3 software for design circuit diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This three software which is listed below is for beginners, that’s means this post is not for professional or advance level user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-for-circuit-diagram-design:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;Software for Circuit Diagram Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-fidocadj:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;1. FidoCadj&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A free graphical editor for (more than) electronics, FidoCadJ is a simple vector graphic editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can draw whatever you want, and FidoCadJ comes with a large library of symbols related to the electrical and electronic engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/FidoCadj.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FidoCadj&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FidoCadJ is a free user-friendly vector graphic editor for MacOSX, Linux, Windows and Android:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A simple schematic capture with a built-in set of electrical symbols and footprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A versatile graphical editor with user-defined libraries;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy-sharing text format for web forums and blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export in several graphical formats: PDF, EPS, SVG, PNG, JPG, and PGF/TikZ for LaTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User interface in English, French, Italian, German, Chinese, Spanish, Czech, Japanese and Dutch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FidoCadj is really simple and light weight program and good news is its in active development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/xJPsJ3&#34; title=&#34;FidoCadj Download&#34;&gt;FidoCadj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-circuit-maker-6-pro:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;2. Circuit Maker 6 Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circuit Maker is the most powerful, easy-to-use schematic capture and simulation tool in its class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using CircuitMaker’s advanced schematic capabilities, you can design electronic circuits and output netlists for TraxMaker and other PCB design tools and autorouters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also perform fast, accurate simulations of digital, analog and mixed analog/digital circuits using CircuitMaker’s Berkeley SPICE3f5/XSpice-based simulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/Circuit-Maker-6-Pro.png&#34; alt=&#34;Circuit Maker 6 Pro&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; As you seen in picture you found a simulation of Collector Coupled Astable Multivibrator. This software containing simulation facility and as a beginner it was my personnel favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/Wa74EM&#34; title=&#34;Circuit Maker 6 Pro Download&#34;&gt;Circuit Maker 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-tinycad:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;3. TinyCAD&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/TinyCAD.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TinyCAD&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TinyCAD is a program for drawing electrical circuit diagrams commonly known as schematic drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It supports standard and custom symbol libraries. It supports PCB layout programs with several netlist formats and can also produce SPICE simulation netlists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also often used to draw one-line diagrams, block diagrams, and presentation drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat or Hierarchical Schematic Entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many popular PCB Layout compatible netlist formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convenient support for embedding graphical images in drawings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/FFylFI&#34; title=&#34;TinyCAD Download&#34;&gt;TinyCAD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>