<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Circuit Diagram on TECHELEX Electronics Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.techelex.com/tags/circuit-diagram/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Circuit Diagram on TECHELEX Electronics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2012-2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 22:56:09 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.techelex.com/tags/circuit-diagram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Software for Design Circuit Diagram</title>
      <link>https://blog.techelex.com/software-design-circuit-diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 22:56:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.techelex.com/software-design-circuit-diagram/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As an electronics engineer designing a circuit diagram is not a big deal. When I was a new student in electronics field teachers teach us to design a circuit diagram using hand, It’s a fun game and i really enjoyed this. But when complexity was increased drawing a circuit diagram using hand is really a bad idea because i want a cleaner tracks and want a better circuit diagram using small piece of PCB (Printed Circuit Board).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that time teachers teach us how to design circuit diagram using software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a time to entered into a software world for designing a circuit diagram it&amp;rsquo;s will amazed you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really amazed like how space saved while designing circuit diagram and simulation of circuit is very interesting. In this post i suggest you a 3 software for design circuit diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This three software which is listed below is for beginners, that’s means this post is not for professional or advance level user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-for-circuit-diagram-design:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;Software for Circuit Diagram Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-fidocadj:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;1. FidoCadj&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A free graphical editor for (more than) electronics, FidoCadJ is a simple vector graphic editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can draw whatever you want, and FidoCadJ comes with a large library of symbols related to the electrical and electronic engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/FidoCadj.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FidoCadj&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FidoCadJ is a free user-friendly vector graphic editor for MacOSX, Linux, Windows and Android:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A simple schematic capture with a built-in set of electrical symbols and footprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A versatile graphical editor with user-defined libraries;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy-sharing text format for web forums and blogs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export in several graphical formats: PDF, EPS, SVG, PNG, JPG, and PGF/TikZ for LaTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User interface in English, French, Italian, German, Chinese, Spanish, Czech, Japanese and Dutch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FidoCadj is really simple and light weight program and good news is its in active development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/xJPsJ3&#34; title=&#34;FidoCadj Download&#34;&gt;FidoCadj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-circuit-maker-6-pro:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;2. Circuit Maker 6 Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circuit Maker is the most powerful, easy-to-use schematic capture and simulation tool in its class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using CircuitMaker’s advanced schematic capabilities, you can design electronic circuits and output netlists for TraxMaker and other PCB design tools and autorouters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also perform fast, accurate simulations of digital, analog and mixed analog/digital circuits using CircuitMaker’s Berkeley SPICE3f5/XSpice-based simulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/Circuit-Maker-6-Pro.png&#34; alt=&#34;Circuit Maker 6 Pro&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; As you seen in picture you found a simulation of Collector Coupled Astable Multivibrator. This software containing simulation facility and as a beginner it was my personnel favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/Wa74EM&#34; title=&#34;Circuit Maker 6 Pro Download&#34;&gt;Circuit Maker 6 Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-tinycad:826e8dfde029d74af9d2b7fae787594d&#34;&gt;3. TinyCAD&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.techelex.com/images/15/12/TinyCAD.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TinyCAD&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TinyCAD is a program for drawing electrical circuit diagrams commonly known as schematic drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It supports standard and custom symbol libraries. It supports PCB layout programs with several netlist formats and can also produce SPICE simulation netlists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also often used to draw one-line diagrams, block diagrams, and presentation drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat or Hierarchical Schematic Entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many popular PCB Layout compatible netlist formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convenient support for embedding graphical images in drawings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download From Here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/FFylFI&#34; title=&#34;TinyCAD Download&#34;&gt;TinyCAD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>